Andy Humes

humes.andrew@gmail.com Denver, CO

Github: https://github.com/humesandrew/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-humes-72075559/



Technical Skills

- React
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- Express
- Node
- MySql
- MongoDB
- Material UI
- Bootstrap
- Handlebars
- Github
- Heroku

Determined, junior level coder versed in many coding languages with proficiency in the front end frameworks. Offers a unique adaptability, stemming from a heavy background in technical skills, complex systems, and analysis. Strong customer service background from many years in health care.

Projects

Java4JavaScripters

https://java4jsrs.herokuapp.com/

This is a MERN application that details our mock company's e-commerce store. We built the back end, front end, and of course made it jive. Or java. Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React, GraphQL, Material UI.

ChartMD

https://chartmd.herokuapp.com/

This is a full-stack application that acts as an electronic practice management system for a simulated doctor's office.

Technologies used: Express, MySQL, Handlebars.

Belly-Buster

https://humesandrew.github.io/Belly-Buster/

This application allows you to look up breweries in any city in America. A map is included as well, should you have a few too many of such breweries.

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Portfolio - React

https://andyhumesportfolio.herokuapp.com/ My portfolio using React and Sass.

Portfolio - JavaScript

https://humesandrew.github.io/portfolio3/ My portfolio using vanilla JavaScript and CSS.

Express Note Generator

https://dashboard.heroku.com/apps/murmuring-spire-00858
An application to track your list of to-do items, using a convenient note-taking system.
Technologies used: Express, Node

Andy Humes

humes.andrew@gmail.com Denver, CO

Github: https://github.com/humesandrew/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andv-humes-72075559/

Education

Certificate of Completion: Full Stack **Coding Bootcamp**

> University of Denver May, 2022

Master of Biomedical Science

Colorado State University

Bachelor of Science: Molecular Biology

The Ohio State University

Bachelor of Arts: Anthropology

The Ohio State University

Volunteer

The Foundation Fighting Blindness

2018 - present Professional Outreach Chair

Chapter Leader - Colorado

True Independence

2018 - present Secretary

Experience

Ophthalmology

2014 - current

- Worked with patients to address their chief complaints and clearly communicated this information to the physicians.
- Ensured a professional demeanor while preparing patients for challenging procedures, conditions, and diagnostic tests.
- Extensive user experience with multiple software systems: electronic health records (EHRs), electronic practice management (EPMs), and electronic data capture (EDCs).
- Assisted the daily operation and coordination of clinical trials on site.
- Developed an electrodiagnostic eye laboratory, performed the tests, and optimized the diagnostic process.
- Arranged low-vision and accessibility services with local providers.
- Ensured that the clinic and our documentation was compatible with accessibility requirements.
- Academic and research activities including paper writing, database management, and statistics.

Colorado Cataract and Laser Aurora, CO

January 2022 - current

Certified Ophthalmic Technician

Colorado Eye Consultants

May 2019 – November 2021

Clinical Research Coordinator Assistant Clinical Manager

Littleton, CO

Certified Ophthalmic Technician

Colorado Retina Consultants Denver, CO

July 2014 - January 2019

Ocular Genetics Coordinator

Lead Technician

Certified Ophthalmic Technician

Biotechnology 2009 - 2014

- Performed experiments at the lab bench in a variety of disciplines, including molecular biology, genetics, biochemistry, and microbiology.
- Kept meticulous records and analyzed massive sets of data, especially focused on genetics.
- User experience with laboratory information systems (LIMS).
- Processed samples for analysis using highly technical scientific procedures.
- Gave input and analysis on designing experiments and optimizing production.
- Performed statistical analysis. Presented research updates to small groups.

SomaLogic, Inc. Boulder, CO Mitomics, Inc. Aurora, CO The United States Bureau of Reclamation Lakewood, CO The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH

Research Assistant I - DNA Sequencing

Research Assistant I - DNA Sequencing

Research Assistant - PCR Specialist

Research Assistant - Biochemistry